请问现在为何都用小灯泡
Let me ask you, Why is everybody using these tiny, little lights nowadays?
我记得以前都用大灯泡
I remember when people used big lights.
钱德爷爷话当年
That's a good story, Grandpa.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
摩妮卡让别人布置她的圣诞树
Wow. Monica's letting other people help decorate her tree?
谁又把她灌醉了吗
Did someone get her drunk again, or...?
圣诞节的意义不在于圣诞树
Having a perfectly decorated tree is not what Christmas is about.
而在于  与所爱的人共度
It's about being with the people that you love.
真好  布置好了
That is nice. And we're done. Ta-da!
我总觉得它少了一股圣诞味
I dunno what it is, It just doesn't quite feel like Christmas to me.
那这样呢
Oh, here.
这样才像圣诞节
See, now it feels like Christmas.
老友记  第六季  第10集  舞林高手
Friends  S06E10  The One With The Routinue
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
（中央咖啡厅）
这就是犹太陀螺的由来
And that's the story of the dreidel.
有些人说圣诞树源自古埃及
Now, Some people trace the Christmas tree back to the Egyptians...
在每年白昼最短的日子  他们会把棕榈枝带进屋里
...who'd bring palm branches into huts on the shortest day of the year...
象征生命战胜死亡
...symbolizing life's triumph over death.
那是4千年前的事了
And that was, like, 4000 years ago.
你开始讲古代  也差不多是那个时候
So, pretty much around the same time that you started telling this story.
大家好  乔伊  怎么了
Hey, you guys. Hey. What's up?
我不出门不行啊  吉宁在房间到处拉筋折腾
I had to get out of the apartment. Janine's stretching all over the place.
随便一转头就看到她在
Everywhere I look she's like...
难怪你无法抗拒
I can see why that's hard to resist.
我好喜欢她
I like her so much.
可惜她对你没感觉
Aw, I'm sorry sweetie that she doesn’t feel the same way.
就是啊  她好可爱
I know. And she's so sweet.
我好想喂她吃葡萄  帮她梳头
I just want to feed her grapes and brush her hair.
你知道她不是猴子吧
You are aware that she's not a monkey, right?
我已经对吉宁没感觉了
I am so over Janine.
我原来觉得她火辣性感  但现在  没这回事了
I mean, Yeah, at first I thought she was hot, but now she's like old news.
你们好  吉宁
Hey, guys. Janine!
我刚接到除夕特别节目的通告
I'm gonna be a dancer on a TV special for New Year's Eve.
叫什么狄克摇滚狄奇之夜的
It's called some sort of Dickin' Rockin' Dicky Eve.
慢着
Hold it.
是《狄克克拉克新年摇滚之夜》吗
Are you talking about Dick Clark's New Year's Rockin' Eve?
那不是我说的吗
Yeah, that's what I said.
天哪  我们爱死那个节目了
Oh, my God, we love that show!
从我有记忆以来  罗斯和我每年都看
Ross and I have been watching it since I can remember.
内心深处的你还是个小胖妹  对吧
Ah, you're still just a little fat girl inside, aren't you?
我今年要去  我要当狂欢派对来宾
Well I'm gonna be on it this year. I'm gonna be one of the party people.
你要去当派对来宾   那些人最酷了
You're gonna be a party person? Those guys rock the most!
他们叫我带人去  你愿意当我的舞伴吗
Well they said to bring someone. Do you wanna be my dance partner?
当然了  我很愿意跟你跨年
Totally! I would love to spend New Year's with you.
明天就要录影了  我也不太懂
Well actually they're taping tomorrow. I don't understand why--
流程是这样的
Well, how it works is...
时代广场的部分是现场直播
...the part with Dick Clark in Times Square is actually live.
但他们会预录狂欢派对的画面
But they tape some of the party stuff ahead of time.
知道的人并不多
Yeah, Not a lot of people know that.
你们也想去吗
Do you guys want to come too?
真的还假的  一言为定
Are you serious? We are there!
你笑什么笑
What are you laughing at?
我跟他交往过  但你还跟她在一起
Well, I used to date him, but you're still going outwith her.
谢谢  那我们就一起去
Thanks. Great, so we can all go together.
我得走了  回头见
I gotta run. catch you later.
再见  吉宁
Bye, Janine.
她是不是约我出去
Did she just ask me out on a date?
应该不是
I don't think so.
什么啊  她找他参加的可是千禧年最盛大的晚会啊
What are you talking about? She invited him to the biggest party of the millennium.
但她也找了你和罗斯
Yeah, but she also invited you and Ross.
很抱歉  那应该不算约会
Yeah, honey, I'm sorry, I don't think that that was a romantic thing.
或许吧  但我有一个办法
Well, maybe. But, hey, I know how I can find out.
我们不是要参加跨年晚会
We're going to a New Year's Eve party, right?
到了午夜  我可以亲她  要是她也回吻  漂亮
So at midnight, I can kiss her. And if she kisses me back, great.
要是她说 "你干什么"
If she says, "Dude, what the hell are you doing?"
我就说 "不是我  都是新年害的"
I can say, "it wasn't me, it was New Year's."
比高中时罗斯想亲我要好
Well, that's a lot better than Ross kissing me in high school...
他说他需要护唇膏
...and saying that he did it because he needed Chap Stick.
那天很干燥
It was a dry day.
我们要上《狄克克拉克新年摇滚之夜》
We are going to Dick Clark's New Year's Rockin' Eve!
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我的天啊
听着  我录过影
Okay, I've been on sets before...
我有些建议
...so let me give you a little advice, alright?
虽然只是上电视  我们只管跳舞  没什么大不了的
It's a show, but we're just dancing. It's no big deal.
最重要的是  耍酷
Important thing to remember: Stay cool.
了解  好
Got it. Okay.
天哪  跟我梦想的一样
Oh, my God! It's just like I dreamed it!
全体集合
Everyone! Gather up!
借过  借过
Excuse us! Excuse us!
我们的做法是  音乐一放  你们就跳舞
Here's what's gonna happen.The music's gonna start, you're gonna dance...
我们会录影  你们不要看镜头  有问题吗
...we'll tape it. Don't look at the camera. Any questions?
我有  什么时候播出
Uh, yeah, I have a question. Uh, when is this gonna air?
好  你们去那边跳
Yeah. Now, uh, you guys dance over there...
你们  去那边跳  你们两个在这里
...you guys, over there. and I want you two right around here,
其他人散开  罗斯
And everyone else, spread out. Ross.
什么时候播出
So when is it gonna air?
你找厨房  我找后面的柜子
Okay, you look in the kitchen, I will look in the back closet.
不必浪费时间了  我在这里
I can save you time, ladies. I'm right here.
钱德  你出去一下  这件事与你无关
Yeah. Chandler why don't you take a walk? This doesn't concern you.
我们在找摩妮卡送的圣诞礼物
We're looking for our presents from Monica.
什么  太差劲了
What? That's terrible!
不会  我们每年都找
No-no, we do it every year!
那就不差劲了
Oh, well, that makes it not terrible.
但我们从来就没找到过
No, yeah, we never find them.
她老是打败我们  奸诈的查某
She's always best at us that wily minx.
放心  我们找个l小时
Don't worry, we're just gonna search here for an hour..
就会换到乔伊那边找  好吗
...and then we'll go to Joey's and search, okay?
不好  你们不能找她送的礼物  我们一定要找
No not okay, You can't look for Monica's presents.But we have to!
你们不一定要找  也不能找  因为我也住在这里
No, you don’t have to, And you can't, because I live here too.
那你应该跟我们一起找
Well, then you should look with us.
为什么
Why?
钱德  你都不愁要送摩妮卡什么吗
Chandler, Aren't you worried about what to get Monica for Christmas?
不会  我有个很棒的构想
No, I have a great idea for a present for her.
就只有  很棒的构想  嗯
Oh, that's it? A great idea? Oh, yeah?
那样是不够的  要是她送你一个大礼
Chandler, that's not enough. I mean what if she gets you a great present...
两个普通礼和一堆小礼呢
...two medium presents, and a bunch of little presents?
而你只送她一个大礼  她一定会很难过
And you've just gotten her one great present? I mean that's just gonna make her feel bad.
那你为什么要让她难过  为什么  为什么
Why would you do that to her Chandler? Why? Why?
有我帮忙  找得更快  没错
If I help, we can find them faster! That's right!
逮到一个了
Ooh! Ooh! We have a live one!
是梅西百货的袋子  对
Oh, it's a Macy's bag! Yeah.
这是给谁的
Aw! Ooh! Who's it for?
"亲爱的  你们真以为我会藏在沙发下
"Dear Losers, do you really think I'd hide presents under the couch?
还有  钱德  我就知道你会让步"
P.S. Chandler, I knew they'd break you."
她可能已经发现了
Uh-oh. She may be onto us.
我们今年一定要找到
We are so gonna find them this year.
你们刚才说会到对面去找   该不会是每年都去吧
Y'know when you guys said you were gonna go across the hall and look. you don’t, you don’t do that every year do you?
是啊
Yeah.
你们没有到我的柜子里面
You don't, like go into the back of my closet...
翻我的健身袋底下吧
...and look under my gym bag or anything?
没有  从来没有
No. Never do that.
乔伊会托我保管东西  我看都没看过
Because that's where Joey gave me some stuff to store that I've never seen before in my life!
刚才的事是幻觉
Okay, that did not just happen.
又有摄影机来了
Okay, here comes another camera.
好  小意思  放轻松
Right. No biggie. Stay loose.
他们为什么一直避开
Why do they keep doing that? Ugh!
想上镜头就得上那些平台
If we wanna get on camera, I think we have to get up on one of those platforms.
他们一直拍平台上的人
They've been taping those people up there all day.
没错
Right.
你们为什么能上去
Hey, what'd you guys do to get up on there?
我们有练过
We learned how to dance.
你练舞时也忘了穿内裤吗
Oh yeah? Well when you learned how to dance did you forget how to put on underpants?
对嘛
Yeah!
你跳得很好嘛  是吗
Hey, you're a good dancer. Really?
臀部再放松一点会更好
Yeah, well you’d be better if you just loosened your hips a little.
怎么说   像这样
What do you mean? Like this.
就是这样  跟着节奏摆动  好多了
That's it. Feel the rhythm. That's better.
你去跟那个女生跳
Okay, you’re dancing with that girl over there.
不  我们是一起来的  我们是一起的
No-no-no-no-no we're together. Yeah, we came together.
我看不出来
I don't see it.
你去跟那个高个子跳  高个子  举手
You are dancing with the tall guy over there. Tall Guy, raise your hand!
不  老兄  拜托让我跟她跳  我很喜欢她  我觉得我有机会
No-no hey buddy, please let me dance with that girl, I really like her and I think I have a shot..
真的  你觉得有  我觉得没有
Really, you think so? I don't.
乔伊那里什么都没   等一下
I couldn't find anything at Joey--Hey-hey, oh hey!
我们找到了
Yeah, we found them.
在客房衣橱的外套后面
They were in the guest room closet behind some coats.
你不必担心了  都是些烂东西
Yeah, and you have nothing to worry about 'cos they're all crap!
那是我要送给你们的礼物
Those are my gifts, I got them for you.
谢谢  钱德  好棒喔
Oh. Thanks, Chandler, they're great!
这个奇怪的金属AZ是什么
Well Chandler, what is this very weird, urn, metal A-Z thing?
那是书挡  是很棒的礼物
Those are book ends. That's a great gift.
好  抱歉  谢谢你送的AZ (AZ音近屁股ass)
Oh. Okay, I'm sorry. Thank you for my "az."
记得都放回衣柜里  好吧
Make sure you put all that stuff back in the closet. okay.
好吗  好啦
Yes, okay.
对了  你人真好  都搬家了
By the way, I just gotta say, I think it's really nice of you that even after you moved...
还帮着乔伊保管东西
...you still keep storing that stuff for Joey.
喂  舞女
Hey, dancing girl?
我想上厕所
Can I go to the bathroom?
来转一下
Here we go. Yeah.
很辣喔  盖勒兄妹
Looking good, Gellers!
还用你说
We know!
你看那个脾气急躁的人  他专门指定上平台的人
Hey, see that snippy guy over there? He's the one who decides who gets up on the platform.
我们应该去他面前跳  好
We should go dance by him. Okay.
全部暂停
Okay, everybody, hold!
接下来上平台的舞者有
Next on the platforms are...
你们两个  还有
You two! And... Yes!
你们两个  酷
You two! Cool!
请问一下
Excuse me? Sir?
如果我不穿内裤会入选吗  摩妮卡
Would it help if I weren't wearing underpants? Monica!
会吗
Would it?
高个子
Hey, Tall Guy!
我想跟你聊聊你的舞伴
listen, I want to talk to you about that girl you're dancing with.
她真不赖   我还差点带老婆来
She's nice, huh? To think I almost brought my wife to this.
是啊  好
Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
老兄   我和她是一起来的
Uh, look buddy, I came with that girl, okay?
我想在新年倒计数时吻她
and I had this plan to kiss her at the new years countdown.
我想追她
I'm trying to win her over. you know--
不行
No I don’t think so.
拜托啦  你可以跟我的舞伴跳
Oh come on man, you can dance with my partner.
她跳得超级棒
she's real, uh, mellow!
你在跟这个女生交往吗
Look, are you dating this girl you came with?
我希望过了今晚可以
I was hoping after tonight that maybe I could you know...
不  不  那就公平竞争  抱歉
No. No. She's fair game if you ask me. Sorry, buddy.
好吧  嘿
All right. Hey.
公平竞争  你说的对  我还能说什么
y'know fair is fair,if you're right, you're right, what can I say,
嘿  不
but hey oh no!
你是小学生吗
Are you in second grade?
喂  尿裤子的是你
Hey, man. You're the one who wet his pants.
嘿
Hey!
烂透了
Man, this sucks.
要是弄得老爸老妈如此嫉妒  最后却没上电视
If Mom and Dad don't see us on TV after we made them jealous...
到时候谁是失败者
...then who's gonna be the losers then?
我知道怎么上平台了  怎样
Hey, I know what'll get us up on a platform. What?
跳招牌舞
The routine!
我们中学毕业后就没跳过了
Ross, we haven't done the routine since middle school.
等那个贱人看过我们的招牌舞
Hey, when the snippy guy sees the routine...
搭都会帮我们搭一座平台
...he'll want to build us our own platform.
有那么赞吗
Was it that good?
我们得了兄弟姊妹组的特别奖
We got honorable mention in the brother-sister dance category!
假午夜快到了  我们还能怎样
It's almost fake midnight. Do we really have any other choice?
那好吧
Okay, let's do it.
爸妈会嫉妒死
Mom and Dad are gonna be so faced!
五  六  七  八
Five, six, seven, eight!
接下来该谁上平台还用问吗
So do we really need to ask who's going up on the platform next?
不用  你们上去照样再跳一遍
Oh no! You get up there and do that again, exactly like that.
好
Yeah! Ooh!
拍下来  当漏网镜头用
Make sure you get this, they’re gonna want it for the bloopers show.
停  全体注意了
All right, cut! Listen up, everyone!
接下来是倒数计时
When we start, it'll be the countdown to new years...
大家要很嗨
...so I want to see everybody's excitement!
喂  兄弟
Hey, guy!
限你3秒钟之内离开我的舞伴
You got three seconds to get away from my partner.
怎么了
What’s going on over here?
你看他的裤子
Take a look at the guy's pants!
你是叫我们要嗨  但他也嗨过头了吧
I mean, I know you told us to show excitement, but don't you think he went a little overboard?
你变态啊   给我滚出场
What's the matter with you?  Get out of here!
滚啦  失禁男
Yeah, take a hike, wet pants!
你相信吗
Can you believe this?
进入千禧年时我们会在平台上
We're gonna be on the platform for the Millennium moment!
就是啊
I know!
你没有偷练招牌舞吧
Hey, you haven't been practicing the routine, have you?
当然没有
No.
我也有
Me too!
回到现场时
When the music starts up again...
我想跳机器人舞步
...I was thinking of maybe goind into the robot, y'know?
罗斯  跳招牌舞就好  免得丢脸
Ross? We should stick to the routine. We don't want to look stupid.
回到现场  倒数10秒
All right, we're back! Ten seconds left here we go!
10   9    8    7
Ten. Nine, eight, seven.
好  这一刻终于来了
Okay, it all comes down to this.
一切顺其自然
Whatever happens, happens.
听天由命
Destiny.
3   2   1
three, two, one!
停  不
"Cut! “No!
快乐
Year!
新年不快乐
Happy No Year!
接着是时代广场的现场画面  大家辛苦了  收工
Okay, here's where we go to the live shot of Times Square,nice work everyone that's a wrap!
嘿  看我找到什么
Hey, look who I found.
你们好
On, hi, guys!
乌类的方向感很好
Y'know, Birds have a very good sense of direction.
或许他们可以帮忙找出礼物
and I thought maybe they could help us find where the presents are hidden.
如果礼物藏在南方过冬的话
Yes, if the presents are hidden south for the winter.
顺着你的笑话去找也行  你知道在哪里吗  当然不知道
Or we could just follow your clever jokes. Any ideas? Didn't think so.
来  把礼物找出来
Come on, show us where the presents are.
鸭子似乎认为摩妮卡送我垃圾
Oh, the duck seems to think that Monica got me garbage.
什么样的回礼能跟垃圾一样好
I wonder what I could get Monica that's as good as garbage.
我的AZ如何
Hmm. How about my “at”?
这是空的  什么
Hey. This is hollow. What?
这排座椅  是空心的  我居然都不知道
This bench, it's hollow. I can't believe I never knew that!
我们的礼物  不要直视它们
Oh, the presents! Don't look directly at them!
什么
What?
没事  不  可以看
All right, no, we could look at them.
这是我的
This one's for me!
这是钱德的  拿去  太好了
This one's for Chandler. Here.
大包的是我的  赶快拆来看
And the big one's for me! Oh, let's open them!
等等  我们不能这样  为什么
Wait a minute. We can't do this. Why?
我不想知道摩妮卡送我什么
I don't want to know what Monica got me.Y'know? I mean,look.
她一定很用心的替我找礼物  想给我惊喜
I'm sure she worked hard at getting it and wanting to surprise me.
你们这样会坏了情绪
And you guys are gonna ruin that.and I,
我们得把礼物放回去  这样不叫圣诞节
look we have to put them back. this is not what Christmas is about.
谁理你  我要拆我的
Whatever, Linus. I'm opening mine.
谁也不准拆
Nobody is opening anything, okay?
但我想看摩妮卡  收到礼物的表情
I want to see the look on Monica's face when I give her my present.
她一定也想看  我收到礼物的表情
I'm sure she wants to see the look on my face when I get mine.
所以求求你们放回去  好吗
So, please, please, can we just...? Can we put them back?
你会送我们更好的礼物吗   好啦
Will you get us better gifts? Fine.
我回来了
Hey, guys.
你们找到礼物了
You found the presents?
钱德  你让她们找到
Chandler, you let them find the presents?
真是的
Great.
你知道那个滤水器多难找吗
Do you know how long it took me to find you that water purifier?
你送我滤水器  这下我懂了  那种表情无价
That's what you got me? Yes, I see. That look is priceless.
甜蜜的家
Home sweet home, huh?
回到现实真好
Nice to, uh, get back to reality.
我们也知道新年会怎样了
Plus, we, uh, know how the New Year's gonna go off.
千禧虫也根本没什么  对吧
I guess there's no reason for all that Y2K panic, you know?
好吧  晚安
Anyway, good night.
乔伊  怎样
Joey? Yeah?
Three...
2  1
...two, one.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
这是干什么
What was that for?
今晚当他们喊卡  我们没能接吻
Tonight when they yelled "cut" and we didn't get to kiss...
我真的很失望  我真的
...I was really, really disappointed, and I just...
真的很想亲你
I just really wanted to kiss you.
真的
Really?
那时候  我也很想亲你  那时候
In the moment, I really wanted to kiss you too. In the moment.
那时候  只有那时候
In the moment. But only in the moment.
你  想再亲一次吗
So do you, uh, want to kiss again?
想啊  离除夕只有两个星期
Sure. New Year's Eve is only two weeks away.
你能等吗
Can you wait?
不能
No.
我也是
Me neither.
3   2
Three, two...
乔伊  不必每次接吻都倒数
Joey, you don't have to count down every time we kiss.
好
Oh. Okay.
但我觉得  我需要几秒钟做准备
Except I sort of felt like I needed a couple seconds to get ready.
我们在平台上  准备带全世界跳进千禧年
We were on the platform, ready to dance into the new millennium...
那家伙却喊了卡
...and the guy yells "cut!"
等等  你们真的跳了
So you guys are telling me that you actually did...
八年级的招牌舞
...the routine from eighth grade?
对  不过当然得稍做修正
Yeah! But of course we had to update it a little bit.
你反应真快  知道要接住我
Hey, by the way, quick thinking about catching me.
我正想说  你们绝不可能
‘Cos I was gonna say there's no way you could've done the end...
照以前的结尾跳
...the way you guys did it back then.
什么  当然可以
What? We could do it.
不行吧  你以前胖的 壮的多了
I don't know. You were a lot bigger-I mean, stronger back then.
我可以  好吗
I can do it, okay?
来吧  我们来试
Come on, let's go! Come on.
l    2    3    4
One, two, three, four...
5    6    7    8
...five, six, seven, eight.
我不行了
I can't do it! Ahh!
那样跳  就能上电视了
Now, you do that, you're on TV.